《法外情真》前情回顾
Previously on The Guardian.
我快要死了
I'm dying...
- 什么  - 肌萎缩性侧索硬化症
- What? - ALS.
卢伽雷氏症
Lou Gehrig's disease.
我一直在想律所的事情
I been thinking about the firm,
是时候让你接手管理合伙人了
It's time for you to be managing partner.
我  我一直都
I, I've always...
试着平等对待每一个人
Try to treat everybody the same.
你试了  但没成功
You may try, but you don't.
你说的那些关于尼古拉斯的话
What you said about Nicolas...
我觉得你是对的
I think you were right,
有的时候
there are times...
我是会偏心他  只想让你知道  呃
I favor him, just want you to know that, uh...
我记住了
I'm gonna keep that in mind.
有什么问题吗
ls something wrong?
没有
No.
我用斯坦霍普的交易为例
I used the Stanhope deal as precedent.
好吧  那是股票交易  这是资产出售
Well, that's a stock deal. This is an asset sale.
那是什么时候的事
When did that happen?
巴特勒现在正在出售资产  这就是作为资产出售交易的原因
Butler's now selling its assets. That's what makes it an asset sale.
好吧  它最开始是股票交易  不是吗
Well, it was originally a stock deal, right?
对  但现在它是资产出售了
That's right, but now it's an asset sale.
好  我会修改的  马上就改
Well, I'll revise it. I'll do it right away.
我爸今天结束前就要一份起草协议
My father's gonna need a draft of this by the end of the day.
如果你不告诉我发生了什么  我就不能起草协议
I can't draft an agreement if you don't tell me what's going on.
没人可以
No one can.
我是说  如果我没有被请去参加会议或者电话会议什么的
I mean, if I'm not invited to the meetings or sitting in on the conference calls...
我花了2100个小时
I billed 2, 100 hours,
带了40万的生意进来
brought in $400,000 in business.
那  那非常好
That's--that's very good.
所以让我来起草协议
So let me revise the agreement
现在我知道了这是资产出售
now that I know it's an asset sale,
然后我们可以假装什么问题都没发生过  好吗
and we can pretend there was never a problem, okay?
我会处理的
I'll do it.
嘿
Hey.
怎么了
What's going on?
我受够了  我是认真的
I've had enough. I mean it.
好  你看  只要坚持到明天  好吗
Yeah. Look, just hang in there until tomorrow, okay?
谢了
Thanks.
抱歉  我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
没事
That's okay.
这个女人  她快把我弄疯了
This woman at work, she's just driving me nuts.
我给了她最简单的工作
I give her the simplest assignments,
不管怎样  她搞砸了然后还怪我
and no matter what, she screws it up and then she blames me.
抱歉
Sorry.
不  没关系
No, don't worry about it.
关于这个孩子的事  不管是男孩还是女孩
About this baby thing, whether it's a boy or girl...
我希望到时候再知晓
I prefer to wait.
你知道  这确实会让人感觉很惊喜
You know, it's just something about it being a surprise.
感觉像作弊了一样
Plus it feels like cheating.
好像在圣诞前夜打开了一个礼物
It's like opening a present on Christmas Eve.
好吧  好  行  我是说  如果你不想知道的话
All right. Okay. All right. I mean, if you don't want to find out.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我只是不能相信你和苏珊娜·佩尔睡过
I just can't believe that you slept with Suzanne Pell.
我不得不一直看到她  你知道吗  我还要和她一起工作
I have to see her all the time, you know? I have to work with her.
然后我怀着你的孩子  你睡着她
And I'm pregnant with your baby, and you sleep with her
有时候  我就是
and sometimes I just...
我不知道  我还是不敢相信
I don't know. I still can't believe it.
- 嘿  儿子  - 爸
- Hey, son. - Dad.
还好吗
How you doing?
还好  呃
Good. Um...
- 都好了吗  - 对
- All set? - Yeah.
嘿  尼克
Hey, Nick.
桑德拉
Sandra.
这样就好了
There you go.
好  我自己走
Yep. On my way.
- 我送你出去  好吗  - 好
- I'll walk you out, okay? - Yeah.
马上回来
Be right back.
过得挺愉快的
Well, that was fun.
- 嗯  谢谢  - 很高兴你能过来
- Yeah. Thanks. - Glad you could come over.
第三季  第二十集
法外真情
翻译  章鱼哥
校对  油 球
特效  转轮 枪
我一直想和你谈谈关于桑德拉的事
Been meaning to talk to you about Sandra.
好
Okay.
她和我在过去几周一直在一起
She and I've been spending a little time together the last few weeks.
什么意思
What does that mean?
这表示我们都很享受在一起的时光
Well, it means we enjoy spending time with one another.
所以你们是朋友吗
So you're friends?
我们享受彼此的陪伴
We enjoy each other's company.
她是个好姑娘
She's a great gal.
和孩子们相处的也好
Real good with children.
她有个女儿  10岁大
She has a little girl, ten years old.
她和香农相处得很好  所以
She gets along great with Shannon, so...
这段关系的时间点似乎还挺巧的  你不觉得吗
The timing of this relationship seems a little convenient, don't you think?
不  不  你不用担心那个
No. No. You don't have to worry about that.
你看  我没计划支持她成为合伙人
See, I wasn't planning on supporting her for partner.
真的吗
Really?
既然这样  你和她在一起的事
And with this, you being involved with her
我就不能再说不了  理由很明显
makes it very dimicult for me to say no, for obvious reasons.
你得做你认为对的事  儿子
You have to do what you think is right, son.
资产购买协议  抱歉  交晚了
Asset purchase agreement. Sorry it's late.
第一稿有些问题
There were some complications with the first draft.
好的  我会看的  然后明早去和巴特勒谈
Okay, I'll look it over, and I'll talk to Butler in the morning.
- 早上好  - 嘿
- Good morning. - Hey.
你想要公司的海盗队的票吗
You want the firm's Pirate tickets?
什么
Excuse me?
我有海盗队比赛的票
I have tickets to the Pirates' game.
噢
Oh.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
- 祝一天愉快  - 你也是
- Have a nice day. - You, too.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
嘿  你好吗  怎么样了
Hey. How are you-- How you doing?
- 没事  - 好  好
- Fine. - Good. Good.
- 呃  我  - 对  一会见
-- Well, I... - Yeah. See you later.
嘿
Hey.
听着  我知道这事不用多说  但是  呃
Listen, I know it goes without saying, but, uh,
如果你不跟别人提桑德拉的事我会很感激的  好吗
I'd appreciate if you don't mention this Sandra thing to anybody, okay?
当然
Sure.
当然卡尔德只给了我们两周时间
Of course Kalder's only giving us two weeks to accept.
但是他为什么会提供那么高昂的溢价
But that's why he's offering such a large premium.
但是就像我说的  查理说了不
But like I said, Charlie said no.
我想他还是做了什么  我是说  他只是不停地摇头
I think he did anyway. I mean, he just kept shaking his head.
如果他都不能理解我说的话事情会很困难
It's hard to know if he even understood what I was saying.
他病的太严重了
He's so sick.
这件事的进展会非常快
The MS has progressed very quickly.
我们可以等到查理同意了
We could wait until Charlie passes.
那我们会错过溢价
We'll lose the premium.
这也是我想说的
I was gonna say that.
有什么其他特殊的理由让查理不卖吗
ls there any specific reason why Charlie won't sell?
没有  这就是事情奇怪的地方了
No. That's why this is so strange.
他一直在合适的时间说要卖掉
He's always talked about selling, at the right time.
努力工作  发展业务  套现
Work hard, grow the business, cash out.
好吧  我们可以用股东协议里的买卖条款
Well, we can invoke the buy-sell clause in the stockholders agreement.
让你合理地买到查理股票
Gives you the right to buy Charlie's stock.
那太浪费时间了
It'd take too long.
好吧
Okay.
我们需要做的是尽快安排一个和查理的律师
What we need to do is to set up a meeting with Charlie's lawyer
见面的会议
as soon as possible.
像我说的  尼克  查理病得很严重
Like I said, Nick. Charlie's very ill.
我不确定那样做能帮上什么忙
I'm not sure that's going to help very much.
好吧  报价两周后就到期了  所以我们别无选择
Well, the offer expires in two weeks, so we have no choice.
你来做决定
Your call.
我打赌离开西南部精神病院的感觉一定很不错
I bet it feels good to be out of Southwestern.
你可不可以把耳机拿掉
Maybe you could take the headphones off.
就一分钟
Just for a minute anyway.
什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
你在用一种  我很担心你的  表情在看我
You're looking at me in that ''I'm so concerned'' kind of way.
没什么  我试过上吊自杀
Big deal. I tried to hang myself.
对  我知道
Yeah, I know.
所以别再像那样看着我了
So stop looking at me like that.
像哪样
Like what?
好像我是疯子一样
Like I'm crazy.
我没有那样看你
I'm not looking at you that way.
我明白你的感受
The truth is I get it.
- 明白什么  - 想自杀
- Get what? - Wanting to kill yourself.
你做过吗
You do?
做过  但那并不不表示
I do, but that doesn't mean--
阿尔文  我能和你谈谈吗
Alvin. Can I talk to you for a second?
现在吗
Now?
对
Yeah.
马上回来  好吗
Be right back, okay?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
德鲁·扬科夫斯基  他13岁
Drew Jankowski. He's 13 years old.
妈妈死于一起车祸  没有爸爸
Mother died in a car accident and there's no father.
他想离开西南精神病院
He's getting out of Southwestern Psychiatric Facility,
而且他需要找个地方待着
and he needs a place to stay.
- 为什么他在西南精神病院  - 他试着自杀了两次
- Why's he at Southwestern? - He tried to kill himself twice.
你反应过度了  露露
You're over-reacting, Lulu.
我可以处理这个孩子的安置听证会  看在上帝的份上
I can handle the kid's placement hearing, for God's sake.
阿尔文  我只是想让尼克接手
Alvin, I just want Nick to take it.
阿尔文最近  有点奇怪
Alvin has been... kinda freaky lately.
我是说  他一直在说来世怎么怎么样的
I mean, he keeps talking about the next life and all that.
所以我不觉得让他来处理这个孩子的事是个好主意
So I don't think it's a good idea for him to work with this kid.
好  听着  关于昨晚  我  呃
Right. Listen, about last night, l, uh--
我不想谈那个  好吗
I don't want to talk about that, okay?
德鲁在会议室
Drew's in the meeting room.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
没  我没事  谢谢
Yeah, I'm okay. Thank you.
我  呃  只是被绊倒了
l, uh, just tripped... over that.
我没事  就是被绊倒了  没什么
I'm okay. I just tripped. No big deal.
第一件我们需要做的就是把你送去收容所
First thing we need to do is to move you into a shelter.
好
Okay.
然后找到和你一起生活的寄养家庭
Then find you a foster family to live with.
最后就知道了上吊为什么没用
Finally figured out why it didn't work.
套索上的线圈不够
Not enough loops in the noose.
线圈可以让它保持住
It's the loops that make it hold.
好吧  我很高兴线圈不够
Well, I'm glad there weren't enough loops.
你不能戴着它进法庭  你得把它拿下来
You can't wear those in the courtroom. You have to take 'em off.
拿下来
Take 'em off!
我们很高兴你能来  尼克
We appreciate where you're coming from, Nick.
但是就像我告诉过你的  查理不想卖
But like I told you, Charlie doesn't want to sell.
这是他的公司
And it is his company.
雷切尔在过去的四年里都是执行总裁
RacheI's been the CEO for the past four years.
查理拥有百分之七十六的股份
Charlie owns 76% of the stock.
格赛特先生有意识到这是格赛特纸业
Does Mr. Gossett realize that this is the best offer
有史以来最好的报价吗
that Gossett Paper will ever see?
尼克是对的  亲爱的
Nick's right, sweetie.
这是个很好的机会  我真的觉得我们应该卖
This is a great opportunity, and I really believe we should sell.
我告诉过你
Like I told you.
我昨晚已经向查理解释过现状了
I explained the situation to Charlie last night.
他传达给我的是  他不想卖
He conveyed to me that he doesn't want to sell.
他传达给你了吗
He conveyed that to you?
尼克
Nick.
对
Correct.
你相信他能明白你在对他说什么吗
And you believe that he understood what you were conveying to him?
是的
Yes.
查理能明白你今天在这里说的每一个字
Charlie understands every single word you've said here today
和你说话时的语气
and the tone with which it was said.
查理是个商人
Charlie's a businessman.
如果他能明白我们说的话
lf he understood what we were saying,
回答 是  就能让他妻子的口袋里多出1500万美元
that saying yes would put an extra $15 million in his wife's pocket,
那么他就会同意这笔交易了
he would agree to the deal.
谢谢你  先生  我想这次的会议可以结束了
Thank you, gentlemen. I think this meeting is over.
- 那家伙完全恍惚了  - 我不这么想
- The guy's completely out of it. - I don't know about that.
我是说  我看见他的眼睛来回地转  有几次他好像还点头了
I mean, I saw his eyes moving back and forth, and he seemed to nod a few times.
不管怎么样  我们需要公开他是无能力者
Either way, we need to have him declared incompetent.
- 无能力者吗  - 对
- Incompetent? - Yeah.
雷切尔需要控制他的股票来完成交易
Rachel needs to control his stock to close the deal.
无能力者的想法相当有损人格  尼克
An incompetency motion is pretty demeaning, Nick.
那  她想卖掉公司
Well, she wants to sell the company.
对  但你不觉得有点过分了吗
Yeah, but don't you think it's pushing a little?
我是说  我完全是个热心派的代表
I mean, I'm all for zealous representation--
我已经提出动议了  我昨天就提了
I've already filed the motion. I filed it yesterday.
你知道  你不觉得在我花了12个小时在读股东协议
You know, don't you think it would've been a good idea
那些细则和公司的规章制度之前
to tell me what you were doing before I spend 12 hours
告诉我你在干什么
reading the the stockholders agreement, the bylaws
是个好主意吗
and the articles of incorporation?
我认为我们是在这儿一起工作的
I thought we were working together here.
我们是
We are.
你想要一些海盗队的票吗
Do you want some Pirates' tickets?
不  谢谢
No, thanks.
嗯  我只有和史蒂夫在一起的美好经历
Well, I haven't had anything but good experiences with Steve.
他很聪明  工作努力  很擅长和客户打交道
He's smart. He's hard working. He's very good with clients.
我同意  我认为他是个有价值的人
I agree. I think he's a valuable addition.
好吧  那么  所有赞成任命史蒂夫·格拉德查克为合伙人的
Okay. So all in favor of nominating Steve Gladchuck for partner
举起你们的右手
raise your right hand.
好
Good.
好的  下一个候选人是桑德拉·凯斯尔
Okay. Next candidate is Sandra Kestle.
我  呃  我喜欢她  我觉得她不错
l, uh...l like her. I think she's great.
杰克呢
Jake?
对  我也喜欢她  她聪明  坚强
Yeah, I like her, too. She's smart. She's tough.
我和她合作得很密切  在她开始和尼克工作之前
I worked with her pretty closely until she started working with Nick.
但  我觉得她很棒
But I think she's great.
尼克
Nick?
嘿
Hey.
嗨
Hi.
我没成功
I didn't make it.
没有
No.
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
很接近了  呃  它没完成
It was close but, uh, it didn't get done.
没完成
Didn't get done.
对
Yeah.
委员会只是觉得你还没有完全准备好
The committee just feels like you're not quite ready yet.
是委员会还是尼克
The committee or Nick?
桑德拉  大家对你评价都很高
Sandra, people think very highly of you.
但不是说评价高就能成为合伙人
But not highly enough to make partner.
还不行  今年不行
Not yet. Not not this year.
尼克说什么了
What did Nick say?
噢  我不能细说
Oh, I can't go into that.
他否决了  是吗
He was negative, wasn't he?
这么说吧  呃
Let me just say that, uh...
所有的意见都非常  非常有利
the consensus was very, very favorable.
有利吗
Favorable?
对
Yes.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
听着  呃  我们今晚什么也不用做
Listen, uh, we don't have to do anything tonight.
不  不  我想
No. No, I'd like to.
那很好
That's good.
- 桑德拉太惨了  - 对
- Too bad about Sandra. - Yeah.
她是个好律师
She's a good lawyer.
但说实话  我很惊讶你会把她拉下来
But to be honest, I was surprised you shot her down.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我发了你一份修改过的资产购买协议
I sent you a copy of the revised asset purchase agreement.
收到了
Got it.
巴特勒签了字  这很好
Butler signed off on it, so that's good.
对
Yeah.
所以我们需要尽快起草结案文件了
So we need to start drafting up the closing documents pretty soon.
好
Great.
他有问你为什么吗
He asked you for what?
他只是说这些事
He just says these things that...
他们很害怕  如果他这么对他们的话
They're scary... if he means them.
但是见鬼  我不是精神病医生
But hell, I'm no psychiatrist.
如果有哪个孩子告诉我他想上吊的话  我会相信的
lf some kid tells me he wants to hang himself, I believe him.
在西南精神病院的医生觉得他只是想引起别的的注意
The psychiatrist at Southwestern thinks he's just looking for attention.
那  我觉得我们应该把他送回去  今天
Well, part of me thinks we should just send him back there... today.
我是说  为什么要搞这种事
I mean, why screw around with this kinda thing?
如果我们做错了什么  他会死的
lf we're wrong about him, he'll be dead.
然后我们就会像两个白痴
And we'll look like a couple of morons.
我正试着让你离开这儿
I'm trying to get you outta here.
这不是玩笑  德鲁
It's not a joke, Drew.
你不能再说关于你自杀的事了
You can't keep talking about killing yourself.
为什么不行
Why not?
因为大家是认真对待你的  即使你不明白
Because people take you seriously, even if you don't mean it.
- 我明白  - 你明白吗
- I mean it. - You do?
你明白了吗  现在呢
You mean it? Right now?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们已经快要帮你找到一个很好的寄养家庭了
We're this close to getting you a very good foster home.
但是你必须停止说自杀的事了
But you have to stop talking about suicide.
如果你不愿意  你就要回到西南精神病院去
lf you don't, you will end up back in Southwestern.
一天关20个小时
Lockdown 20 hours a day.
这里不是真正的天堂
This place isn't exactly paradise.
我打电话给卡尔德的律师了
I put in a call to Kalder's lawyer.
好  我已经告诉他了
Yeah, I already talked to him.
他们说不能延长报价时间
Said there's no way they'll extend the offer.
- 好  - 那无能力者的议案可以实施了
- Okay. - So the incompetency motion's at noon.
尼克 我还是觉得如果我们遵守买卖协议的条款
Nick, I still think if we followed the terms of the buy-sell agreement--
如果委托人想卖  才是最有效的方法
lf the client wants to sell, this is the most emective way to get there.
好的  谢谢
Great. Thanks.
你知道  我不是你的员工  我是合伙人
You know, I'm not your associate. I'm a partner...
生意比你做的多  我要说的是
with more business than you, and what I am saying is
我真的  真的不喜欢别人来告诉我该怎么做
I'm really, really not so great about being told what to do anymore.
- 在
- Yeah?
嘿
Hey.
爸  我只是  呃  我只是想告诉你那个
Dad, I just, uh... I just wanted to tell you that...
我的投票  我的意见与你和桑德拉之间的关系无关
my vote, my opinions had nothing to do with your relationship with Sandra.
我希望你能明白这点
I hope you understand that.
我只是觉得她是个一般的律师
I just think she's an average lawyer.
所以你不同意她在过去的三年里
So you disagree with the excellent evaluation
得到的优秀评价吗
that she received over the last three years?
如果他们觉得她很优秀  那就同意
lf they characterize her as excellent, then yes.
总体评价从1分到5比4
Overall rating on a scale of one to five: four.
评价说  桑德拉是一名出色的律师
Comments: ''Sandra is an excellent lawyer.
继续前进的步伐  她是个有价值的人才
Continues to make great strides. She's a valued asset.''
对  我知道这是我写的  那是  呃  两年前写的了
Yeah, I know what I wrote. That was, uh... That was two years ago.
好吧
Well...
她昨晚辞职了
she quit last night.
说得通
Makes sense.
等等  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
什么叫说得通
What the helI's that supposed to mean?
拜托  爸  我的意思是  她开始和执行合伙人约会
Come on, Dad. I mean, she starts dating the managing partner
就在合伙人投票前几周
a few weeks before the partner vote.
她没被选上  然后就退出了
She gets passed over and then she quits.
她的做法很聪明
It's very clear what she's doing.
尼古拉斯  你错了
Nicholas, you are wrong.
那她为什么辞职
Then why did she quit?
我不确定我能不能做得到
I'm not sure I can do this.
我只是不想它
I just don't think it's the...
如果他真的明白发生了什么
What if he really does understand what's going on,
然后他不想卖掉公司呢
and he doesn't want to sell the company?
好  那  有别的选择  我们可以买下他的股票
Right. Well, there are other choices, and we can buy out his stock--
我们已经谈过了  杰克
We've already talked about that, Jake.
那要花3个月的时间  卡尔德的报价会被扔进垃圾桶
It'll take three months, and Kalder's offer would be in the trash.
雷切尔  我们说的是1500万美元
Rachel, we're talking about $15 million here.
就是感觉不对
It just feels wrong.
这是你的选择
It's your choice.
你觉得我们应该这么做吗
You think we should do it?
如果你想卖掉公司  你应该这么做
lf you want to sell the company, you should.
听着  如果查理有能力的话
Listen, if Charlie were competent,
你认为他会拒绝这样的报价吗
do you think that he would turn down an offer like this?
不会
No.
好了  你有答案了
Well, there's your answer.
法官阁下  根据他的妻子和护理人员提供的证词
Your Honor, based on testimony presented by his wife and caregivers,
很明显  格赛特先生已经没有能力
it is clear that Mr. Gossett is no longer capable
去评估与他财产有关的重要信息了
of evaluating crucial information pertaining to his estate.
他是病人  法官阁下  很严重的病
He is sick, Your Honor. Very sick.
他在交流方面有困难  但他是清醒的  他的思想是有意识的
He has a dimicult time communicating. But he is aware, and his mind is alert.
格赛特先生知道有一份报价  法官阁下
Mr. Gossett knows there is an offer on the table, Your Honor.
他简单地选择了说  不
He is simply choosing to say no.
欧文先生希望查理·格赛特是头脑清醒的
Mr. Irving wants Charlie Gossett to be lucid,
这样他就能说服自己他是清醒的
so much so that he's convincing himself that he is.
我的意思是  我对枫树也可以做同样的事
I mean, we could do the same thing with a maple tree.
你看着它足够久的话  它就会移动
You stare at it long enough, it will move.
你竟敢
How dare you!
很遗憾  法官阁下  很遗憾
It is sad, Your Honor. It is sad.
但是格赛特先生在身体和精神上都不在场
But Mr. Gossett is not mentally or physically present,
这样他不应该被允许管理他的财务状况
and he should not be allowed to manage his financial affairs.
所以  如果我们想的话我们可以接受那份报价卖掉公司
So, we can accept the offer and sell the company if we want.
对  没错
Yes, that's right.
好
Okay.
像你说的  我们已经没有别的选择了  是吧
Like you said, we really didn't have any other choice, huh?
我会安排一个和卡尔德的会议商量剩下的细节
I'll set up a meeting with Kalder to go over the remaining details.
好
Good.
我还是觉得这是个糟糕的决定
I still think it was a bad call.
- 我们赢了  - 对
- We won. - Yeah.
我们把自己和事务所  都放到了尴尬的境地
We embarrassed ourselves and the firm.
- 嘿  - 嗨  伯顿
- Hey. - Hi, Burton.
- 你好吗  - 挺好的
- How you doing? - Good.
你饿了吗
Are you hungry at all?
事实上  我饿坏了
I'm starving, as a matter of fact.
来个三明治吧
How about a sandwich?
- 好  进来吧  - 谢谢
- Yeah, come on in. - Thank you.
那  桑德拉  我有个主意
So, Sandra, I got an idea.
你为什么不  呃  回来工作呢
Why don't you, uh, come back to work?
伯顿
Burton...
我明白你为什么心烦  我真的明白
I understand why you're upset. I really do.
但是我不能相信 我们不能想到可以
But I can't believe we can't think of something
解决这些事情的方法
that makes some sense to work this out.
你知道  你已经离成为合伙人那么接近了
You know, you were so close to making partner.
好吧  我不想看到你丢下这些离开
Well, I hate to see you throw that all away.
明年  顺便说一下  我认为你会成功的
Next year, by the way, I think that you're gonna make it.
我很感激  但是
I appreciate that, but...
不  我觉得我做了一个正确的决定
No, I think I've made the right decision.
真的  我感觉相当好
Truth is, I feel pretty good about it.
那  你已经有别的安排了吗
Well, you have something lined up already?
还没有
Not yet.
如果你想  你知道我很乐意帮你排忧解难
lf you want, you know I'd be happy to help you out.
我在这个镇上还是认识一些人的
I still know a few people in this town.
我会让你知道的
I'll let you know.
好吧  那我问你
Well, let me ask you this.
我们的关系对你的决定有任何影响吗
Did our relationship influence your decision at all?
我辞职的决定和我们的关系没有任何关系
My decision to resign had nothing to do with us.
好
Good.
这对我来说很重要
That's important for me to know.
- 阿尔文  你有拉布隆特的文件吗  - 尼克  进来吧
- Alvin, do you have the LaBonte file? - Nick, come on in.
没事  我只是在找那份文件
No, I'm just looking for that file.
我今天早上在那个ALS的网站上
I was on that ALS site this morning.
和一个家伙聊天  奥哈拉
I was talking to a guy, O'Hara.
然后  奥哈拉今天早上起来  他的手臂发麻
So, O'Hara wakes up this morning, and his arm is tingling.
他只是躺在床上  想喝杯咖啡  他的手臂就发麻了
He's just lying there in bed, about to have a cup of comee, and his arm's tingling.
他说这是他感觉最可怕的事情
Said it was the most frightening thing he ever felt
因为这是第一个迹象  一个开始
because it was the first sign, the beginning.
对
Right.
在这些留言板上  很多人都在谈论自杀
On these message boards, a lot of people talk about suicide.
互相给对方提示  建议
Give each other tips, suggestions.
奥哈拉说这是条很好的界限  因为如果你做的太早
O'Hara says it's a fine line, because if you do it too soon,
你可能会错过剩下的最后一点快乐
you may miss out on the last little slice of happiness.
但如果你等得太久  你就会失去完成的机会
But if you wait too long, you lose the ability to pull it off.
爬上椅子  跳出窗外
Climb up on a chair. Out a window.
你有拉布隆特的文件吗
Do you have the LaBonte file?
去露露的办公室试试
Try Lulu's office.
嗨  弗兰克·汤姆林森  汤姆林森塑料厂的
Hi. Frank Tomlison. Tomlison Plastics.
- 您有预约吗  - 有  来见伯顿·法林
- Do you have an appointment here? - Yes, to see Burton Fallin.
我的秘书  琼  上周做了预约
My secretary Joan made it last week.
您好  我是伯顿·法林
Hello, I'm Burton Fallin.
你被传唤了
You've been served.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
好吧  桑德拉刚刚给我们发了传票和诉状
Well, Sandra just hit us with a summons and complaint.
她声称受到了性别歧视
She's claiming sexual discrimination.
歧视
Discrimination?
主要在于你和她之间的关系
Primarily based upon your relationship with her.
什么  你在说什么
What? What are you talking about?
看一下诉状
Read the complaint.
一些指控说了你对待她的方式非常非常
Some of the allegations she makes about the way you treated her
令人困扰  尼古拉斯
are very, very disturbing, Nicholas.
嘿
Hey.
既然你带了午餐过来  那我就带晚餐来了
Since you brought over lunch, I figured I'd take care of dinner.
进来吧
Come on in.
伯顿
Burton...
你今天来的时候我就想和你说关于诉讼的事
when you came over today I wanted to tell you about the suit.
好吧
Okay.
但是我说不出口  我太不安了
But I couldn't. I was too nervous.
走到像你这样的人面前我说不出  抱歉
It's not that easy to walk up to a guy like you and say,
但是你的儿子是个傲慢自大的混蛋  这样的话
''Excuse me, but your son is an arrogant jerk.''
我是说  他是你儿子
I mean, he's your son.
对  他是我儿子
Yeah, he is my son.
而且他  他是个好男人
And he's a... he's a good man.
是个好律师
He's a good lawyer.
他很难搞  我知道
He's tough, I know that.
但他不会性别歧视
But he's not a sexist.
那他为什么不投票给我
Then why didn't he vote for me?
那你在发诉讼之前为什么没有告诉我呢
Why didn't you tell me what was going on before you filed that suit?
为什么要在我离开后做这些
Why did you go behind my back?
- 伯顿  - 我本来可以搞定一切的
- Burton-- - I could've fixed everything.
我已经气愤了很久了
I've been so angry for so long.
当我没被选上的时候  我只是
When I got passed over, I just...
打给我的律师  我说  去做吧
I called my lawyer. I said, ''Let's do it.''
好吧
Well...
有个办法能让大家都赢
There is a way out so everybody wins.
你是让我撤回诉讼吗
Are you asking me to drop the suit?
是的
Yes, I am.
我不能这么做
I can't do that.
我应该走了
I should probably go.
对  我想  那是对的
Yeah, I guess that... that makes sense.
嗨  我们需要谈谈
Hi. We need to talk.
我不觉得这是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea.
是因为我还是因为我爸
ls this about me or my father?
因为你
It's about you.
好吧  那和执行合伙人约会看来只是个小巧合了
Well, it seems a little coincidental that you'd be dating the managing partner--
- 太可笑了  我们是朋友  - 朋友吗
- That's ridiculous. We're friends. - Friends?
没有什么阴谋  尼克
There's no conspiracy here, Nick.
我喜欢你父亲的陪伴  只是这样  没有其他的
I enjoy your father's company, that's all. There's no agenda.
这次的诉讼和他没有任何关系  是因为你
This lawsuit has nothing to do with him. It has to do with you.
我
Me?
是我从法学院把你招进来的
I'm the one that hired you out of law school.
一个36岁的一级助理  我给过你机会了
A 36-year-old first year associate. I gave you your chance.
你很可笑
You're ridiculous.
我可笑
I'm ridiculous?
你知道  如果我是你最大的困扰
You know, if I'm your biggest problem,
那你只要回来和杰克工作就好了
then just come back to the firm and work with Jake.
不  谢谢
No, thank you.
如果你再联系我的话  我会向州律师协会提出投诉
lf you contact me again, I'll file a complaint with the State Bar.
嘿  尼克
Hey, Nick.
你觉得你在做什么鬼事情
What the hell do you think you're doing?
去桑德拉的家里找她吗
Going over to Sandra's house like that?
好吧  我只是
Well, I was just--
我在试着和她进行合理的谈话
I was trying to have a rational conversation with her.
没起作用
It didn't work.
那  你在期待什么
Well, what'd you expect?
你看过诉状了吗
Did you read the complaint?
看了  看了
Yeah. Yeah.
上面写的是真的吗
ls it true?
尼古拉斯  你有没有对她做过她说的那些事
Nicholas, did you do the things she alleges you did or not?
好吧  如果我做了  那也不是故意的
Well, if I did, it wasn't intentional.
儿子  你要回答我  有还是没有
Son, you gotta answer me yes or no,
我  我不知道
l--l don't know...
我可能说了一些我不该说的话  但是
I might've said some things that I shouldn't have but...
那不是因为她是个女人
it's not because she's a woman.
噢  所以你就对待别人像对待垃圾一样  你是这个意思吗
Oh, so you just treat everybody like crap. Is that what you're saying?
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
我觉得我们应该去伴侣心理辅导
I think we should go to couples counseling.
噢
Oh.
我是说  很明显  呃  我对一些事还是非常不安
I mean, I'm obviously, uh, still very upset about certain things.
对
Right.
所以我想心里辅导可能会有帮助
So I think it might help.
好  我  我不知道
Yeah. l--l don't know.
你知道  我希望我们可能可以  呃
You know, I'd hoped that we could maybe, uh...
先一起解决问题
work things out together first.
对  但是那个策略并没有很成功
Yeah, but that strategy hasn't been very successful.
我只是不太擅长应付治疗
I'm just not very good with therapy.
我知道  但是如果我们能坐下和某个人
I know, but maybe if we go and sit down with someone
谈谈这个问题  也许会有帮助的
and talk about this stuff, it will help.
对  但  我有段不愉快的经历  呃
Right. Well, I have a hard time, um...
坐下来和我不认识的人聊天
sitting down talking to a person that I don't know...
而且我还要付钱
and that I'm paying.
好吧
Okay.
苏珊娜和德鲁·扬科夫斯基的寄养家庭吵架了
The foster family that Suzanne was talking to for Drew Jankowski fell out.
他们很紧张关于自杀的事
They were nervous about the suicide thing.
那个我提到的家庭  他们改变主意了
That family that I mentioned, they changed their minds.
没关系
Doesn't matter.
我真的觉得我可以做到
I really think I might do it.
只要尽快完成
Just get it over with.
跟我来
Come with me.
- 为什么  - 跟我来就行了
- Why? - Just come with me.
放下耳机
Leave that here.
把耳机放下
Just leave it here.
你就待在这儿
You just wait here.
我就离开2分钟
I'm gonna be about two minutes.
我能通过玻璃看到你
I can see you through the glass.
- 阿尔文  - 什么
- Alvin. - What?
你还在ALS网站上吗
You still on the ALS site?
呃  没有  就是做些工作
Uh, no, just doing some work.
- 嘿  你打断我了  - 我需要你的帮助
- Hey, you disconnected me. - I need your help.
你看  我有两张海盗的票  位置很好
Look, I have two Pirates' tickets, great seats.
你需要我帮你去看海盗队的球赛吗吗
You need my help to go to a Pirates' game?
不  我需要你帮助一个委托人
No, I need your help with a client.
那个孩子
The kid.
- 自杀的那个吗  - 对  德鲁
- The suicidal one? - Yeah. Drew.
露露不想我接这个案子
Lulu doesn't want me to take that case.
我想
I do.
我们需要给卡尔德一份过去三年所有审计过的财务报表
We need to get Kalder a copy of all the audited finances for the last three years.
我知道
I know.
以及未解决诉讼的摘要
And a summary of outstanding litigation.
呃  做完了
Uh, done.
很好
Great.
你有  呃
Have you, uh...
你有看过桑德拉的诉讼吗
Have you read Sandra's complaint?
看了
Yeah.
里面有一些相当严重的指控
Some pretty serious allegations in there.
雷切尔·格赛特刚才打电话来了
Rachel Gossett just called.
她不能来开这个会了
She's not gonna be able to make the meeting.
她的丈夫去世了  几小时前
Her husband died a few hours ago.
噢
Oh.
谢谢
Thank you.
干嘛
What?
没什么
Nothing.
他的死不是我们的错
It's not our fault he died.
当然不是
Of course not.
好了
Okay.
好吧  我希望玩得开心  就算海盗队输掉了
Well, I hope you had a good time, even though the Pirates lost.
是啊  差点儿赢了
Yeah. It was close.
10比1吗
10-1?
德鲁
Drew.
所有我们今晚聊的这些  你的妈妈  那些孩子
Everything we talked about tonight, your mom, those kids--
怎么了
Yeah?
很痛苦
It's hard.
太痛苦了
人可以是卑鄙的
People can be mean.
对
Yeah.
人也会死亡
And people die.
这很难过
And it's sad.
如果你想  我可以接受你的案子
lf you want, I can take over your case,
帮你找到合适寄养家庭
help you find the right foster home.
那个叫尼克的怎么办
What about that Nick guy?
他会理解的
He'll understand.
好
Okay.
在这期间
ln the meantime,
如果你在想伤害你自己的事情时  能先打电话给我的话  我会很高兴的
if you're thinking about hurting yourself, I'd appreciate it if you'd call me first.
好的
Okay.
好
Great.
明天见
See you tomorrow.
- 在吗
- Yeah?
有时间吗
You have a minute?
当然
Sure.
这是个艰难的谈话
This is a difficult conversation,
所以如果可以的话  我就直说了
so I intend to speak candidly, if that's all right.
你想说什么
What's on your mind?
我们几个今天吃午餐的时候在讨论桑德拉的诉讼
A few of us had lunch today to discuss Sandra's lawsuit.
你们几个
A few of you?
好吧  执行委员会  除了你和尼克
Well, the executive committee, minus you and Nick.
我们决定聘请外部律师
We've decided to retain outside counsel.
不让我做顾问吗
Without consulting me?
考虑到指控说的  伯顿
Considering the allegations, Burton,
我们觉得最好别把你牵扯进来
we figured it was better to leave you out of it.
我们已经聘请了贝丝·雅各布森  她是一名劳工律师
We've hired Beth Jacobson. She's a labor attorney.
她的名气很大
She's got a great reputation.
她想在早上和尼克见面
She wants to interview Nick in the morning.
总之  我只是想在我们采取行动之前让你知道
Anyway, I just wanted to let you know before we made a move on this.
听起来像是你已经开始行动了  杰克
Sounds like you're already moving on it, Jake.
桑德拉主张说你曾经让她帮你在一家叫Lucque的饭店
Sandra claims that you once asked her to make a reservation for you
预订过房间
at a restaurant called Lucque's.
呃  对  我是  呃
Uh, yeah, I was, uh...
我开会迟到了
I was running late into a meeting,
然后我记得我答应过把客户带到那儿
and I remembered that I promised to take a client there.
接着就  我让她帮我预定了  这没什么
And yeah, I asked her to make a reservation. No big deal.
所以你让她打了电话吗
So you asked her to call?
对
Yes.
你以前有让男同事打电话去预约吗
Did you ever ask a male associate to call and make a reservation?
呃  呃
Uh... uh...
我不知道  不记得了
I don't know. I don't know.
呃  我不知道
Uh... I don't know.
什么是从来不回电话或者邮件
What is this never returning phone calls or e-mails thing?
所以是真的喽
So it's true?
你知道  有时候我工作的时候  我喜欢自己做事情
You know, sometimes when I'm working, I like to do things myself.
你不回复在你手底下工作的人的电话或者邮件吗
You don't return calls or e-mails from people who work under you?
你有过不回男同事的电话十次吗
Have you ever not returned 10 calls from a male associate?
噢  够了  我  我不知道
Oh, come on. l--l don't know.
我没法把这些事都记录下来
I don't keep a record of these things.
四个月前你有把桑德拉踢出客户会议吗
Did you kick Sandra out of a client meeting about four months ago?
对  我  我让她离开了
Yeah, l--l asked her to leave.
在一个重要的男性执行总裁客户的面前吗
ln front of a male CEO of an important client?
她  她拖延了会议的进度
She was--she was slowing down the meeting.
她问了很多无意义的问题  而我试着把注意力集中在这个工作上
She was asking pointless questions, and I was trying to focus on the job.
是的  我要求她离开了
And yes, I asked her to leave.
你告诉她  滚出去
You told her to ''Get out.''
我是让她离开
I asked her to leave.
再一次表示我的哀悼  葬礼办得很好
Again, my condolences. It was a beautiful service.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们可以坐下来谈一谈
We are going to have to sit down and talk--
不
No.
公正的合伙人进行了投票
The disinterested partners took a vote,
我们决定尽快与桑德拉达成和解
and we've decided to settle with Sandra as quickly as possible.
是吗
Really.
跟她闹上法庭我们没好处  理由很明显
There's no upside to litigating this with her, for obvious reasons.
好吧  我同意这个说法
Well, I don't disagree with that.
我们还安排了2点的会议讨论尼克的情况
We've also scheduled a meeting for 2:00 to discuss Nick.
讨论尼克什么
Discuss Nick?
他的态度  他的保证
His attitude. His commitment.
还有他的时间
And his hours.
他做兼职赚了很多钱  伯顿
He gets paid a lot of money to work part-time, Burton.
你现在是在告诉你试着在争取足够的投票来开除我儿子吗
Are you telling me you're trying to round up enough votes to fire my son?
不
No.
我是在告诉你我们安排了2点的会议讨论关于尼克的事
I'm telling you that we've scheduled a meeting for 2:00 to discuss Nick.
葬礼的事怎么样了
How was the funeral?
我和情感顾问约好了明天下午见面
I made an appointment with a couples counselor for tomorrow afternoon.
好的
Okay.
呃  好像人们  呃
Uh, it seems people, uh...
我想我眼中的自己和别人不一样  我觉得
I see myself differently than others do, I think.
总之  如果你觉得太晚的话
Anyway, if you don't think it's too late then--
没有  没有太晚
No, it's not too late.
好
Okay.
那时候我向你求婚的时候你为什么说  不
Why did you say no when I asked you to marry me?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许我们可以在我们咨询的时候谈
Maybe we can talk about that when we...
- 噢  对  - 好
- Oh, yeah. - Okay.
噢  顺便说一句
Oh, and by the way,
我看到那条裙子了
I saw the dress.
我很高兴是个女孩
I'm glad it's a girl.
我就期待是女孩
I was rooting for a girl.
- 尼克  - 阿尔文
- Nick. - Alvin.
我为德鲁找了一个很棒的寄养家庭
I found this great foster family for Drew.
很好
Great.
所以  如果你不介意  我想接手他的案子
So, if you don't mind, I'd like to take over his case.
可以  但是不要告诉露露
Yeah. But just don't tell Lulu.
- 嘿  - 嘿
- Hey. - Hey.
- 有时间吗  - 有
- You got a second? - Yeah.
听着  我想为发生在桑德拉身上的事道歉
Listen, I wanted to apologize for what happened with Sandra.
你知道  我希望我没有搞砸你和她之间的事
You know, I hope I didn't screw things up for you and her.
没有  我们问了那个律师  贝丝  会尽快和解这个诉讼  所以
No. We asked that lawyer, Beth, to settle it as quickly as possible, so--
- 如果你觉得那是最好的  - 是的
- If you think that's best. - I do.
怎么了
What's going on?
有个执行委员会的会议
It's an executive committee meeting.
他们没有叫我
They didn't call me.
你没被邀请
You weren't invited.
他们要开除我吗
They gonna fire me?
他们在讨论这个
They're talking about it.
他们有选票了吗
They have the votes?
杰克觉得有了
Jake thinks so.
我的意见可能还有些用
My opinion might still mean something.
你要投哪一票
Which way are you gonna vote?
好了  别闹了
Well-- Don't be ridiculous.
不  我是认真的
No, I'm serious.
儿子  你是个非常好的律师
Son, you're a very good lawyer.
对  如果我不是你的儿子  你会投哪一票
Yeah, if I weren't your son, which way would you vote?
但你是我的儿子  而且你是个了不起的律师
But you are my son, and you're a hell of a lawyer.
好吧  你还没有回答我的问题  爸
Well, you're not answering my question, Dad.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I think?
我认为你应该做对事务所最有利的事
I think you should do what's best for the firm.
我是说  我觉得你应该做对事务所最有利的决定
I mean it. I think you should do what is best for the firm.
好
Right.
Xgun擦枪小组 有偿招募译制成员 诚邀阁下
加入Q群：545053435
请注明职务：翻译、听译、aegisub特效（熟练手）
对字幕有任何意见和建议的同学请加Q群：544487177